A Guide to the Papers of B.F.D. Runk, ca. 1925-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of B.F.D. Runk ca. 1925-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12715-m
Ca. 200 items (1 box).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library in a bequest from the Estate of B. F. D. Runk April 14, 1995 through Raymond C. Bice, Jr. and A. G. Gilliam, Jr.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the papers of University of Virginia Dean Benjamin Franklin Dewees Runk, ca. 1925-1994, ca. 200 items (1 Hollinger box) including diplomas and certificates of Dean Runk chiefly from his many years at the University of Virginia, but also a number from his service with the United States Coast guard; family and other photographs; news clippings about Dean Runk and local towns; greeting cards from B.F.D. Runk; information about "Hollymead" and "The Union" belonging to Runk and his sister; personnel files on Runk's World War II service in the Coast Guard Reserve; and the Miller School. Also included are the memorial resolution for Runk composed by Raymond C. Bice and presented to the University faculty, and copies of the program from his memorial service, 1994.
Contents List
- "A Brief History of the Early Years of the Miller Manual Labor School" by B.F.D. Runk 1973 (Folder 1)
- Certificates, Awards, etc. 1925-1981 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence 1968, 1988 (Folder 3)
- Greeting Cards from B.F.D. Runk and his sister, Betty Kayan n.d. (Folder 4)
- Information and Maps concerning "Hollymead" and "the Union" n.d. (Folder 5)
- Legal and Financial Papers 1936, 1967 (Folder 6)
- Memorial Program and Resolution in Memory of Mr. B.F.D. Runk 1994 (Folder 7)
- News clippings 1969-1985 (Folder 8)
- Papers concerning the Receipt of the First Annual Samuel Miller Memorial Award by B.F.D. Runk 1988 (Folder 9)
- Photographs of the Farm Operations at "Hollymead" ca. 1940s, n.d. (Folder 10)
- Photographs of B.F.D. Runk 1963, 1976, n.d. (Folder 11)
- Photographs of World War II and Miscellaneous ca. 1940s (Folder 12)
- United States Coast Guard Reserve Personnel Files 1942-1945 (Folder 13)
- United States Coast Guard Reserve Personnel Files 1942-1945 (Folder 14)